<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="teibp.xsl"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>unknown title</title><author>unknown author</author></titleStmt><editionStmt><edition><date>unknown date</date></edition></editionStmt><publicationStmt><p>unknown</p></publicationStmt><sourceDesc><p>Converted from a Word document</p></sourceDesc></fileDesc><encodingDesc><appInfo><application xml:id="docxtotei" ident="TEI_fromDOCX" version="2.15.0"><label>DOCX to TEI</label></application></appInfo></encodingDesc><revisionDesc><listChange><change><date>2018-03-06T21:44:02Z</date><name>unknown author</name></change></listChange></revisionDesc></teiHeader><text><body><p>TEI Boilerplate</p><p>	TEI Boilerplate is a digital publishing platform that allows the transformation of Text Encoding Initiative P5 documents into stylized websites without the use of server-side processing or directly changing the documents from XML documents to HTML documents. TEI Boilerplate was created by John Walsh, Grant Simpson, and Saeed Moaddeli at Indiana University. The first and only version was released in 2012, and has been maintained since then, with the files being actively worked on in January of 2018.</p><p>TEI Boilerplate uses a wide range of technologies to change TEI XML documents into stylized websites. The main technology that it uses is XSLT, and the power of modern day browsers. Modern day browsers have built in XSLT version 1.0 built into their software and TEI Boilerplate uses this to translate the TEI XML document into a HTML5 shell with elements that are common in HTML such as clickable links, and embedded images. Similar to HTML, TEI Boilerplate uses CSS to stylize the documents. The only technical requirement of TEI Boilerplate is a modern browser, and it currently works with current versions of Firefox, Chrome, Safari, and Internet Explorer.</p><p>There are several projects that use TEI Boilerplate. One of these projects is the TAPAS Project. TAPAS project allows users to display, store, and share their TEI documents. One of the tools that the TAPAS project uses to display these TEI documents is TEI Boilerplate. Another project that uses the TEI Boilerplate is one of John Walsh’s own projects, the PetrArchive. The PetrArchive is a collaboration between John Walsh and Wayne Story, professor of Italian at Indiana University and is an archive of 366 poems from Petrarch. TEI CAT, or Critical Apparatus Toolbox is a toolbox for a larger project of digital humanities at a university in France. It uses the stylesheets from TEI Boilerplate as a basis for it’s display. That is about the scope of projects that use TEI Boilerplate. It does not seem to have a lot of use through the internet.</p><p>	TEI Boilerplate is pre-configured almost to completion. A person with a small amount of technical skills can use it because everything that needs to be done to turn TEI documents into a website is already in the code. However, it does require that the user have a server or a website where the files can be uploaded. I personally installed it on a GitHub page and was able to upload my TEI XML documents into the folder where I uploaded them. It also requires knowledge of CSS if the user wants to customize any of the pre-loaded templates that come with TEI Boilerplate. TEI Boilerplate prefers TEI P5 XML documents for it’s content. TEI P5 XML documents are the only type of documents that will work with TEI Boilerplate.  </p><p>I feel like I got pretty far when I attempted to work with TEI Boilerplate. I used documents from Indiana University’s Victorian Women Writers Project, which I knew had TEI documents in it because I have used it at my workplace to preview documents that I have personally encoded in TEI.  I was able to download a document from this website in XML and change it into a TEI Boilerplate stylized website. However, I could not get the links in this document to go to the proper place on the page. I also used a TEI document from my own work with the University Faculty Council. It displayed the information in a stylized way, however, I noticed that it didn’t exactly look like what it suppose to be, such as the fact that a list was suppose to be numbered using letters, and it was numbered with numbers instead. I also took some other file formats and turned them into TEI then transformed them using TEI Boilerplate, and this was useful.</p><p>	There are many strengths and weaknesses to using TEI Boilerplate. One of the strengths of TEI Boilerplate is the fact that is it lightweight and makes it easy to process TEI XML documents into rich stylized websites without having to use XSLT to transform them into HTML. It also is great for teaching TEI, it allows the users to see what their documents look like right away without having to publish them, edit them, and publish them again. The strengths of TEI Boilerplate could also be it’s weaknesses. Your document has to be a TEI document in order for it to be processed and changed by TEI Boilerplate. While there are many tools that allow you to change your documents from one format to TEI P5, such as OxGarage, knowledge of these tools is necessary. </p></body></text></TEI>
