<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="teibp.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 http://www.dlib.indiana.edu/lib/xml/ufc/minutes.xsd"
   xml:id="InU-Ar-c180-U06-1978">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>University Faculty Council Circular U06-<date when="1978">1978</date>
            </title>
            <title type="gmd">a machine-readable transcription</title>
            <funder>Indiana University Faculty Council</funder>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Transcribed from the original record by</resp>
               <!--Insert proper name, i.e. Nicole Mares-->
               <name>Matthew Malher</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Indiana University Archives</authority>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Herman B Wells Library E460</addrLine>
               <addrLine>1320 East 10th Street</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Bloomington, Indiana 47405</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Phone: 812-855-1127</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Fax: 812-855-8104</addrLine>
            </address>
            <publisher>Indiana University Libraries</publisher>
            <!--changed publisher value from "Indiana University, Digital Library Program" 6/2017 per schema rules- Mary Mellon-->
            <pubPlace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubPlace>
            <availability status="unknown">
               <p>Copyright interests for this set of minutes belongs to the Trustees of Indiana
                  University. For more information, contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>
            </availability>
            <!--Insert date of minutes in RLG format, ie. 2003-09-19-->
            <date when="1978-03-28">1978-03-28</date>
            <!--Replace [idno] with collection ID number and date of meeting in RLG format ie. InU-Ar-c180-1984-04-18. 
Add date to id type attribute as well.-->
            <idno type="InU-Ar-c180-U06-1978">InU-Ar-c180-U06-1978</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>
               <ref target="http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/archives/ufc/1978-03-28">March 28,
                  1978<!--Month 00, Year--></ref>
            </note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>University Faculty Council Circular U06-<date when="1978">1978</date>, C180,
               Indiana University Archives.</bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <!--States how and under what circumstances corrections have been made in the text.-->
            <!--Use the correction tag to document any corrections you make from the text
     version to the electronic version. i.e. spelling errors or typos.  
     This includes the paragraph and item sections as well.-->
            <correction status="unknown" method="silent">
               <p>Corrections made from original document using corr and sic tags</p>
            </correction>
         </editorialDecl>
         <p>Created in machine-readable format from Microsoft Word file using OxGarage utility.</p>
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change who="Matthew Malher, Indiana University" when="2018-02-26">Encoding
            started.</change>
         <change who="Matthew Malher, Indiana University" when="2018-02-26">Encoding
            completed.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>

   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="circular">
            <head>REVIEW PROCEDURES FOR UNIVERSITY ADMINISTRATORS</head>
            <p rend="right">Circular U6-78</p>
            <p>[The University Structure Committee intends to present a motion at the March 28
               meeting that the wording of this Circular U6-78 replace Circular U4-78. Then the
               discussion during our meeting would be based on the text of this document, rather
               than the earlier one.]</p>
            <p rend="center">REVIEW PROCEDURES FOR UNIVERSITY ADMINISTRATORS</p>
            <p><hi rend="u">Resolution #1:</hi></p>

            <p>Administrative officers holding positions that bear directly on the system-wide
               teaching/research mission of the university shall have their performance and the
               performance of their office evaluated regularly by a process referred to as Review.
               The Review shall apply to those officers/offices reporting directly to the President
               and Executive Vice President of Indiana University.</p>
            <p><hi rend="u">Resolution #2:</hi></p>
            <p> The Review shall be conducted early in the fifth year in office and in recurring
               intervals of three years thereafter. </p>
            <p><hi rend="u">Resolution #3:</hi></p>
            <p> The President shall announce, at the last meeting of each year of the University
               Faculty Council, the list of all those officers who will be subject to review the
               following year as well as the respective appointing officer(s). When an
               administrator's duration of service necessitates Review, the official to whom that
               administrator most directly reports shall be the appointing officer of a Review
               Committee. Because the positions to be reviewed bear directly on the teaching and
               research mission of the university, a majority of the members of the Review Committee
               shall be from the faculty. Further, in reviewing a chief administrative officer for a
               particular campus, a majority of members of the Review Committee shall be chosen by
               the apointing officer from a list of faculty on that campus recommended by an
               appropriate faculty body. The number of faculty recommended from among the
               Bloomington, Indianapolis, and regional campuses shall be in rough proportion to the
               degree these campuses fall under the jurisdiction of the administrative position
               being reviewed. The University Faculty Council's Nominations Committee will be
               charged with submitting a list of prospective Review Committee members for approval
               by the University Faculty Council for submission to the appointing officer. The list
               should contain roughly one-third more names than requested by the appointing officer,
               so as to provide the appointing officer some choice in appointing faculty to the
               committee. In addition to receiving nominations for the Review Committee from the
               University Faculty Council, the appointing officer is expected to solicit nominations
               from appropriate representative student bodies as well as nominations drawn from
               other appropriate constituencies. </p>
            <p><hi rend="u">Resolution #4:</hi></p>
            <p> Appointing officers shall make their requests for the creation of Review Committees
               in such a manner that ample time is available for the process. Ordinarily, a Review
               Committee should be appointed at least one semester before the date the report is
               due. </p>
            <p><hi rend="u">Resolution #5:</hi></p>
            <p> The appointing officer and the Secretary of the University Faculty Council shall
               convene the Review Committees. The Review Committee shall establish its own operating
               procedures. The appointing officer will cooperate with the Review Committee to assure
               that the administrator under Review meets reasonable requests by the Review Committee
               for information. The appointing officer would normally be expected to provide the
               Review Committee with a description of the duties and responsibilities of the
               administrator under Review as well as arranging for reasonable and adequate staff and
               financial support for the activities of the Review Committee. </p>
            <p><hi rend="u">Resolution #6:</hi></p>
            <p> The Review Committee shall make its report in writing to the appointing officer. The
               report shall consist of a narrative and critique, a summary of the committee's
               findings, and recommendation(s). The appointing officer shall meet with the Review
               Committee and discuss his/her response to the recommendations of the committee. The
               Review Committee shall make a report to the University Faculty Council in Executive
               Session, summarizing the Review. </p>
            <p><hi rend="u">Resolution #7:</hi></p>
            <p> The Trustees of Indiana University are urged to accept regular review as desirable
               for the offices of President and Treasurer and that consultation with faculty, staff,
               and students of the university as well as other university constituencies is an
               important part of these Reviews. Furthermore, the Trustees are urged to acknowledge
               the Review Committee as a useful method of consultation. Furthermore, the Trustees
               are urged to take advantage of the process outlined herein for the creation of
               faculty membership of a Review Committee for these offices. In these cases, the
               President of the Board of Trustees would act as the appointing officer and the
               recipient of the Review Committee's report. </p>
            <p><hi rend="u">Resolution #8:</hi></p>
            <p>The University Faculty Council recommends that local campus faculty councils/bodies
               consider promulgating procedures for the review of their campus-wide administrative
               offices/officers.</p>

         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
